Nicolas Trinephi

oxdot nicolas.trinephi@imperial.ac.uk

in /in/nicolastrinephi

9 @live:nicolas_6754

① /ntrin

□ +1(949)-329-3603

% https://ntrin.github.io/

Irvine, California

SUMMARY

Master's graduate in computational science with industry experience in deep learning algorithms applied to time series prediction using cloud data flow tools such as Databricks. A team player and results driven individual, I am searching for my next opportunity in data science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant: Applied Computational Science *Imperial College London - London, UK (Remote)*

Sep 2020 - Present

- Drove student learning by holding office hours to walk through solutions, methods and key concepts.
- Maintained academic excellence through mentoring 10 students on work habits and mental health with 1 on 1 meetings.

Data Science Intern June 2020 - Sep 2020

Wintershall DEA - Hamburg, Germany

- Streamlined project management and decision making by performing statistical and bi-variate analysis of 13 years
 of raw industrial oil production data on Azure Databricks using PySpark.
- Enabled more effective data comprehension and analysis by designing interactive visualization of the data in Python using Plotly and HVplot.
- Successfully forecast production rates with 99% accuracy by applying various LSTM recursive neural networks using Keras and MLflow.
- Formalized and communicated results by conducting a company-wide L3 presentation using PowerPoint.

Primary Mentor May 2019 - July 2019

UCL MechSpace - London, UK

- Ensured the success of projects such as the Hydrone Hydrogen Racecar by coaching students on design and technical platforms such as CAD and ARDUINO systems.
- Oversaw the safety of the workshop by supervising working students, facilitating machine operations, and training students in processes such as 3D printing and laser cutting.

EDUCATION

Master's of Science: Applied Computational Science

Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

Imperial College London - London, UK

- Relevant Coursework: PyTorch Classification and Transfer Learning, Optimisation, Numerical Methods, C++ Advanced Programming
- · Thesis title: Deep Learning in Virtual Flow Metering

Bachelor's of Engineering (Hons): Mechanical Engineering with Finance

Sep 2016 - July 2019

University College London - London, UK

• Thesis title: Particle Suspensions in Microfluidic Applications

PROJECTS

Cifar10 Py 2020

Imperial College London

Placed in the top 10 (score of 0.8) by applying PyTorch transfer learning with EfficientNet to classify over 10,000 images in a school Kaggle competition.

Conway's Game of Life in Parallel C++

2020

Imperial College London

Implemented Game of Life in parallel using C++ MPI and object oriented programming wherein the number of cores is adaptive to user's input with a post processing script developed in Python.

SKILLS

Languages Native English and French, conversational Spanish

Programming Python, C++, MATLAB, Bash, LATEX, HTML, MySQL, Dox BAT

Packages Keras, PyTorch, PySpark, MLflow, sklearn, XGBoost, Plotly, HoloViews, C++ MPI Technical Databricks, Apache Spark, Microsoft Office, GitHub, CATIA V. 5, Origin Pro